<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-08-16T18:55:03-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">U.S. Web Design System</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/feature/2016/02/12/web-design-standards.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="U.S. Web Design System" /><published>2016-02-12T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-02-12T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feature/2016/02/12/web-design-standards</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/feature/2016/02/12/web-design-standards.html"><![CDATA[<p>A collaboration between the U.S. Digital Service and 18F, the U.S. Web Design System is the U.S. government’s very own set of common UI components and visual styles for websites. I work as a front-end developer on the project. We designed this resource to make things easier for government designers and developers, while raising the bar on what the American people can expect from their digital experiences.</p>

<p>We wanted to create a single reference point for developers in need of common patterns, providing the building blocks of code for teams to assemble websites. Our goal was to build a system of components shaped by modern best practices in front-end development and government accessibility standards.</p>

<p>We built the UI components on a solid HTML foundation, progressively enhanced to provide core experiences across browsers. All of the code is 508 compliant, so it’s accessible to everyone. Our styles are written with Sass and can be used as a Sass library or included directly as compiled CSS. In order to make sure our code was easy to read and easy to pick up, it had to look like it was written from a single voice. After speaking with dozens of front-end developers and designers in government, we sought to strike a balance between modular CSS and code that’s clean and easy-to-use.</p>

<p>Read more on the <a href="https://18f.gsa.gov/2015/09/28/web-design-standards/">blog</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="feature" /><category term="front-end development" /><category term="design systems" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I worked as a product manager, designer, and developer on the U.S. Web Design System, a design system for the federal government which are available to the public to promote consistent, accessible federal websites.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/uswds/home.png%22,%20%22/img/work/uswds/colors.png%22%5D" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/uswds/home.png%22,%20%22/img/work/uswds/colors.png%22%5D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Demand Clean Power</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/feature/2014/10/12/demand-clean-power.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Demand Clean Power" /><published>2014-10-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-10-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feature/2014/10/12/demand-clean-power</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/feature/2014/10/12/demand-clean-power.html"><![CDATA[<p>Demand Clean Power is a national campaign by the Natural Resources Defense Council and Robert Redford to tell President Obama to reject the Keystone XL pipeline and promote clean energy instead. It attracted hundreds of thousands of visits at launch.</p>

<p>I had the privilege to do the front-end development and implement animations of beautifully crafted icons which enter the screen as you scroll through the website.</p>

<p>Studio and photo credits: verynice</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="feature" /><category term="front-end development" /><category term="interaction design" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I led frontend development for a national campaign for the National Resource Defense Council that received hundreds of thousands of visits at launch. By using subtle animations, we were able to bring storytelling elements to life and engage users to sign the petition rejecting the Keystone XL pipeline.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/demand-clean-power/dcp-home-01.png%22,%20%22/img/work/demand-clean-power/dcp-home-02.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/demand-clean-power/dcp-verynice-phone.jpg%22%5D" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/demand-clean-power/dcp-home-01.png%22,%20%22/img/work/demand-clean-power/dcp-home-02.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/demand-clean-power/dcp-verynice-phone.jpg%22%5D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Homebase</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/feature/2014/10/10/homebase.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Homebase" /><published>2014-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feature/2014/10/10/homebase</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/feature/2014/10/10/homebase.html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="background--problem">Background / Problem</h3>

<p>San Antonio is 296 years old. It is home to many old neighborhoods in various states of revitalization. The homes and businesses in these neighborhoods face significant structural and visual problems, like crumbling foundations, leaking roofs and busted floors.</p>

<p><em>Difficulty accessing grants and incentives</em></p>

<p>There are many financial incentives available to property owners to improve their homes and offices/retail spaces. These grants have complex eligibility rules and are administered by a number of different organizations. It’s an opaque process that frustrates users.</p>

<p><em>Confusing permit and regulation system</em></p>

<p>The city has set down a number of regulations intended to improve the aesthetic of neighborhoods and ensure home improvements are done safely. These rules are poorly explained and almost impossible to navigate without expert help.</p>

<h3 id="research">Research</h3>

<p>We discovered our problem through explorations of the cities’ most challenged neighborhoods and discussions with San Antonio residents who face significant hurdles in improving the quality of their homes.</p>

<p>Community partners, including SA2020, the Westside Development Corporation and others stressed the deep strain put on neighborhoods by crumbling homes. We discovered that structural issues like holes in walls and slipping foundations prevented homeowners from heating their homes in the winter and cooling them in the summer.</p>

<p>Homeowners told us of the difficulty they had finding the right contractors and navigating the rules to perform these projects. Many don’t have access to the cash to complete all the repairs required on their homes, and leave much-needed repairs for another time.</p>

<h3 id="solution">Solution</h3>

<p>Our project will make it easy to apply for permits, find grants, and pick the right contractors to work on home repair projects. We believe these three elements are the key to encouraging people to take the first step toward improving their homes.</p>

<p>In the long term, we’d like to see our tool used to revitalize neighborhoods and make residents proud of the place they live.</p>

<p><em>First steps</em></p>

<p>We’re currently equipped to help homeowners get a few basic projects started by connecting them with the permits they need for the project. We’ve reformatted the current experience, which requires users to sort through cryptically-named PDF applications that arbitrarily group together different repairs. Our tool starts with the project – users can select the repairs they want to complete, like adding a room – and moves forward from there.</p>

<p><em>Next steps</em></p>

<p>We are exploring a few possible next steps, including integrating our app with the city’s backend to allow users to send their permit application with the click of a button, and to easily track its status online. We’re also investigating how to catalogue available grants and create a standard application process for them.</p>

<p><em>Measuring success</em></p>

<p>Our key metric to test our app against is improving the number of home repair permits applied for in the core downtown area. This area is home to challenged neighborhoods, some in states of deep disrepair.</p>

<p>This metric was set forth by SA2020 as part of their Neighborhoods cause area, which is focused on improving the housing stock in San Antonio’s urban core and making the whole city a great place to live.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="feature" /><category term="design" /><category term="development" /><category term="branding" /><category term="strategy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a Code for America fellow, I developed Homebase, a web application to renovate housing safely and efficiently for residents in San Antonio. With an easy step-by-step online process, we reshaped how the city provides services and empowered residents to own the city they live in.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/homebase/homebase-bizcards.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/homebase/homebase-mockup.jpg%22%5D" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/homebase/homebase-bizcards.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/homebase/homebase-mockup.jpg%22%5D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mobile Orchestra</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/other/2014/10/08/mobile-orchestra.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mobile Orchestra" /><published>2014-10-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-10-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/other/2014/10/08/mobile-orchestra</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/other/2014/10/08/mobile-orchestra.html"><![CDATA[<p>Mobile Orchestra is a way to visualize bikers in Critical Mass. We forked Jono Brandel’s <a href="http://patatap.com">Patatap</a> and created music loops from it that are associated with a person. As each person enters the bike group, a piece of their music loop gets played, as they leave, it gets removed. This creates a live, sonic representation of music. I also created the beats.</p>

<p>Team members: Drew Wilson, Ainsley Wagoner, Jason Denizac, Peter Welte, Jeremia Kimelman, Maksim Pecharsky</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="other" /><category term="design" /><category term="development" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I created Mobile Orchestra to represent with sound moving bike groups, like Critical Mass. Loops from Jono Brandel’s Patatap stream into the group as bikers enter the group.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/mobile-orchestra/mo-home.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/mobile-orchestra/mo-jamming-1.png%22,%20%22/img/work/mobile-orchestra/mo-jamming-3.png%22,%20%22/img/work/mobile-orchestra/mo-clouds.jpg%22%5D" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/mobile-orchestra/mo-home.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/mobile-orchestra/mo-jamming-1.png%22,%20%22/img/work/mobile-orchestra/mo-jamming-3.png%22,%20%22/img/work/mobile-orchestra/mo-clouds.jpg%22%5D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dante’s Inferno</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/other/2014/09/29/dante's-inferno.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dante’s Inferno" /><published>2014-09-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-09-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/other/2014/09/29/dante's-inferno</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/other/2014/09/29/dante's-inferno.html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a book I made for my Typography class using Dante Inferno’s text. To make the book, we had various restrictions from font size, style, color that were removed each week. I wanted to mirror motifs like the nine circles of hell and used text to create flames, rings, gates and more.</p>

<p>The first part is the process book, the second part uses photography from my travels abroad in Italy. I made the book with Japanese Stab Book Binding in purple and silver string.</p>

<p>UCLA | Design Media Arts</p>

<p>Teacher: Gail Swanlund</p>

<p>TA: Mattia Casalegno</p>

<p>Watch the <a href="https://vimeo.com/11486287">video</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="other" /><category term="design" /><category term="print" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a book I made for my Typography class using Dante Inferno’s text. To make the book, we had various restrictions from font size, style, color that were removed each week. I wanted to mirror motifs like the nine circles of hell and used text to create flames, rings, gates and more.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/dante/dante-photo-01.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/dante/dante-pages/dante-page-text-fire.jpg%22%5D" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/dante/dante-photo-01.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/dante/dante-pages/dante-page-text-fire.jpg%22%5D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Jr. Philharmonic Orchestra of California</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/09/28/jr-philharmonic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jr. Philharmonic Orchestra of California" /><published>2014-09-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-09-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2014/09/28/jr-philharmonic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2014/09/28/jr-philharmonic.html"><![CDATA[<p>I had the privilege to design the poster for the Jr. Philharmonic Orchestra of California 75th anniversary Diamond Jubilee concert.</p>

<p>The Jr. Phil was one of the oldest young people’s symphony orchestras in the United States. The orchestra was commited to changing the lives of young people via classical music. More than 10,000 musicians, ages 12 through 25, have been selected for membership in the orchestra. The symphony touched the lives of thousands of young people from diverse social, economic and ethnic backgrounds.</p>

<p>The goal of these designs was to highlight the beautiful Walt Disney Concert Hall, designed by Frank Gehry, which the concert was taking place in as well as honor conductor-founder Dr. Ernst Katz, who had passed away after 72 years of conducting the orchestra. These prints were featured inside the Walt Disney Concert Hall. This was also the final concert of the Jr. Phil and was honored to perform live on percussion as well. The orchestra had a profound effect on my life and was glad to give something back.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="design" /><category term="print" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I had the privilege to design the poster for the Jr. Philharmonic Orchestra of California 75th anniversary Diamond Jubilee concert.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/jr-phil/jp-outside-poster.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/jr-phil/jp-poster.jpg%22%5D" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/jr-phil/jp-outside-poster.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/jr-phil/jp-poster.jpg%22%5D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Custom Typography</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/other/2014/09/28/custom-typography.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Custom Typography" /><published>2014-09-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-09-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/other/2014/09/28/custom-typography</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/other/2014/09/28/custom-typography.html"><![CDATA[<p>This is some custom typography a created for a book project for Dante’s Inferno. I enjoyed exploring how removing and cutting out space could define letter forms and how we perceive letters. I also layered in photography I took while in Italy to add another sense of place and light within the letters.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="other" /><category term="design" /><category term="print" /><category term="typography" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is some custom typography a created for a book project for Dante’s Inferno. I enjoyed exploring how removing and cutting out space could define letter forms and how we perceive letters. I also layered in photography I took while in Italy to add another sense of place and light within the letters.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/dante/dante-blue.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/dante/dante-type-photo.jpg%22%5D" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/dante/dante-blue.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/dante/dante-type-photo.jpg%22%5D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Swipes for the Homeless</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/other/2014/09/27/swipes-for-the-homeless.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Swipes for the Homeless" /><published>2014-09-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-09-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/other/2014/09/27/swipes-for-the-homeless</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/other/2014/09/27/swipes-for-the-homeless.html"><![CDATA[<p>Swipes for the Homeless is a non-profit organization consisting of a coalition of university and college chapters located throughout the world. Their mission is to tangibly and tactically partner with college campuses to alleviate hunger while raising young people’s awareness of homelessness and hunger through education and outreach.</p>

<p>Swipes has been recognized by The White House, Forbes, The Case Foundation, GOOD and other influencers as a benchmark for positive change on America’s college campuses and an emerging leader in the non-profit field of hunger awareness and alleviation. In 2012, Swipes for the Homeless was awarded the Campus Champions of Change by Barack Obama and the White House.</p>

<p>I had the privilege to lead development, implement responsive designs for tablet and mobile phones, and develop the <a href="http://swipesforthehomeless.org/swipeouthunger/">Swipe Out Hunger</a> campaign which aggregates social media posts with hashtags #swipeouthunger.</p>

<p>Studio credit: verynice</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="other" /><category term="development" /><category term="responsive design" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I developed the website for Swipes for the Homeless, a White House honored organization that collects unused meal swipes from university students and delivers food to local shelters.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/swipes/swipes-home.png%22,%20%22/img/work/swipes/swipes-iphone-mockup.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/swipes/swipes-swipeouthunger.png%22%5D" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/swipes/swipes-home.png%22,%20%22/img/work/swipes/swipes-iphone-mockup.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/swipes/swipes-swipeouthunger.png%22%5D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SF Living Innovation Zones</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/other/2014/09/26/liz.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SF Living Innovation Zones" /><published>2014-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/other/2014/09/26/liz</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/other/2014/09/26/liz.html"><![CDATA[<p>The Living Innovation Zone Program (LIZ) makes it possible to use public space in new and exciting ways. By enlivening public spaces with art installations, these spaces become places for people to stop, engage, and enjoy urban life.</p>

<p>I worked on the LIZ project with the San Francisco Mayor’s Office of Civic Innovation to make a more open project curation process for LIZ’s. We decided to divide the website into spaces and ideas. Spaces were existing locations a person could explore, envision their art there, and then apply for the space. Ideas were where user ideas would live and be open for the public to vote on their favorite idea. We developed a system to show when a space was available or filled so users could see if they wanted to apply or explore.</p>

<p>Partner: San Francisco Mayor’s Office of Civic Innovation</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="other" /><category term="design" /><category term="concept" /><category term="development" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I designed and developed a tool for the Living Innovation Zones project with the San Francisco Mayor’s Office of Innovation. The website lets people discover and vote on ideas for new projects, creating vibrant spaces in the streets they live in.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/liz/liz-ipad-mockup.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/liz/liz-inner.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/liz/liz-all.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/liz/liz-iphone-mockup.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/liz/liz-art.jpg%22%5D" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/liz/liz-ipad-mockup.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/liz/liz-inner.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/liz/liz-all.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/liz/liz-iphone-mockup.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/liz/liz-art.jpg%22%5D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Skillcamp</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/other/2014/09/25/skillcamp.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Skillcamp" /><published>2014-09-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-09-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/other/2014/09/25/skillcamp</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/other/2014/09/25/skillcamp.html"><![CDATA[<p>Skillcamp is a learning space that helps navigate you through civic technology training.</p>

<p>With my team, I created a website that provides education resources around civic technology. I did the frontend development of the site as well as worked with designers and illustrators to create a fun and friendly look and feel. I really enjoyed the campy look and coming up with the navigation that acts as live sign-posts. Going through the lesson, is as easy and friendly as creating a new lesson.</p>

<p>Team members: Alex Tran, Molly McLeod, Dan Getelman, Drew Wilson</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="other" /><category term="frontend development" /><category term="UX" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Skillcamp is a learning space that helps navigate you through civic technology training.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/skillcamp/skillcamp-home.png%22,%20%22/img/work/skillcamp/skillcamp-lesson.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/skillcamp/skillcamp-lesson-new.png%22%5D" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/img/work/skillcamp/skillcamp-home.png%22,%20%22/img/work/skillcamp/skillcamp-lesson.jpg%22,%20%22/img/work/skillcamp/skillcamp-lesson-new.png%22%5D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>